luxology.com 2019-07-15

# 

FOUNDRY VISIONMONGERS LTD
     PRIVACY NOTICE

CONTENTS
1.   PURPOSE AND SCOPE .....................................................................................................3
2.   NOTICE STATEMENT ........................................................................................................3
3.   ROLES AND RESPONSIBILITIES ..........................................................................................3
4.   DEFINITIONS ....................................................................................................................4
5.   THE PERSONAL DATA WE COLLECT ................................................................................5
6.   WHAT WE USE YOUR PERSONAL DATA FOR AND WHY ..................................................6
7.   SOURCES WE COLLECT YOUR PERSONAL DATA FROM ...................................................7
8.   WHO WE SHARE YOUR PERSONAL DATA WITH ..............................................................8
9.   TRANSFERRING YOUR DATA INTERNATIONALLY...............................................................9
10.  AUTOMATED DECISION MAKING AND PROFILING ..........................................................9
11.  HOW LONG WE KEEP YOUR DATA................................................................................10
12.  YOUR RIGHTS IN RELATION TO YOUR PERSONAL DATA ...................................................10
13.  COOKIES ........................................................................................................................11
14.  SECURITY .......................................................................................................................12
15.  CHANGES TO THIS NOTICE ...........................................................................................12
16.  CONTACT AND COMPLAINTS ........................................................................................13

1.      PURPOSE AND SCOPE
The Foundry Visionmongers Ltd (“Foundry”, “we”, “us”) is committed to protecting Personal Data
and the processing of such data, in accordance with applicable Data Protection Laws.
When you engage with us via our website or through our marketing activities, and when you buy or
use our products and services we will collect certain information that can be used to identify you.
We collect and use personal data about you in order to manage our relationship with you and to
fulfil our legal duties. We recognise that we have a duty to ensure that we are open and transparent
with you and that we enable you to exercise your choices and preferences in relation to that data
quickly and easily.
In relation to the way in which we process your personal data, Foundry is a “data controller”. This
means that we are responsible for deciding how we hold and use personal information about you.
This Privacy Notice (the “Notice”) governs how Foundry collects, stores, uses, retains and shares
personal data. It explains which data is collected and for what purpose. It also lists what rights you
have as an individual, and who you should get in touch with if you have questions or concerns.
2.      NOTICE STATEMENT
Everyone has rights with regard to how their personal data is handled. When you use our websites,
when you interact with us directly or via our marketing, and when you purchase and use our products
or services we will collect, store and process personal data about you. We recognise the need to
treat that personal data in an appropriate and lawful manner.
This is our Notice for our services. It explains your statutory rights and how we collect and use your
personal data. It describes the processing activities that are carried out by Foundry, the purposes for
which these activities are performed and the legal bases that Foundry relies upon to justify these
processing activities.
3.      ROLES AND RESPONSIBILITIES
Foundry’s Cyber Security and GDPR Steering Committee (the “Committee”) has overall
responsibility for ensuring compliance with applicable Data Protection Laws and with this Notice.
If this Notice does not answer your questions, or if you consider that we have not followed this Notice
in respect of your personal data, then you can get in touch with the Committee by contacting
Foundry’s Head of Legal and General Counsel by phone, email or post and we will be happy to help.

                 How to contact us                                         Details
   Phone                                            +44 (0)20 7479 4350
   Email                                           legal@foundry.com
                                                   The Head of Legal and General Counsel
                                                   The Foundry Visionmongers Ltd.
                                                   5 Golden Square
   Address
                                                   London
                                                   W1F 9HT
                                                   United Kingdom
4.     DEFINITIONS
Applicable Data Protection Laws the General Data Protection Regulation (EU) 2016/679 (GDPR) and
any associated regulations or instruments, plus other local data protection laws, regulations,
regulatory requirements and codes of practice applicable in the jurisdictions Foundry offices are
located. Or, any other legislation, regulations, rules and codes of practice that transpose or
supersede the above including any data protection laws amending, replacing and superseding the
GDPR in the United Kingdom following exit from the European Union.
Committee Foundry’s Cyber Security and GDPR Steering Committee.
Data Subjects for the purpose of this Notice include all living individuals about whom Foundry holds
personal data.
Data Controllers are the people who or organisations which determine the purposes and manner in
which any personal data is processed. They have a responsibility to establish practices and policies
in line with applicable Data Protection Laws. Foundry acts as a data controller in respect of some of
the personal data processed within our business.
EEA refers to the European Economic Area
Personal Data means data or information relating to an identifiable natural person. An identifiable
natural person is one who can be identified directly or indirectly, in particular by reference to an
identifier such as a name, an identification number, location data, an online identifier or to one or
more factors specific to the physical, physiological, genetic, mental, economic, cultural or social
identity of that natural person.
Processing is any activity that involves use of the data. It includes obtaining, recording or holding
the data, or carrying out any operation or set of operations on the data including organising,
amending, retrieving, using, disclosing, erasing or destroying it. Processing also includes transferring
personal data to third parties.

Websites means our websites at www.foundry.com, www.madewithmischief.com and www.athera.io.
5.    THE PERSONAL DATA WE COLLECT
We collect personal data over the course of our relationship with you when you use our websites,
when you interact with us directly or via our marketing, and when you purchase and use our products
or services.
We collect the following types of Personal Data:
•     Contact details: information that allows us to contact you directly such as your name, job title, the
      company you represent, email address, telephone number and billing and shipping addresses
      associated with your account.
•     Payment information: credit/debit card details, bank account details and any other information you
      provide to make payment for the products and services you purchase from us.
•     Purchase and account history: when you arrange trials or purchase products or services from us, we
      keep records relating to those orders.
•     Records of your discussions with our teams: when you share comments and opinions with us, ask
      us questions or make a complaint we will keep a record of this. This includes when you send us
      emails, interact with us on social media or contact our support desk.
•     How you use websites: when you use our Websites, we collect information about where you are
      visiting from, your interests, the pages you look at and how you use them.
•     Website security: when you register with our Websites we store your account details and password.
      When you buy products or submit forms via our Websites we keep records of your acceptance of
      our end user license agreements and privacy notices.
•     Advertising and direct marketing: through our social media, marketing events, advertisements and
      direct marketing, we collect information about your interests, how you respond to, or interact with,
      any marketing or advertising communications directed to you, and any requests for these
      communications to stop.
•     Product usage: when you use our products, we collect personal data about how and when you
      make use of them, your license, your computer equipment and network environment including
      information about the location of that equipment and whether you make use of any of our other
      products or services on your computer.
•     Exercising your rights: if you exercise any of your statutory rights under Applicable Data Protection
      Laws, we will keep a record of this and how we respond.

•       Account information: we keep copies of the emails you send us and we create identification
        numbers that allow us to link your account status with your order history, product licenses and
        payments.
6.      WHAT WE USE YOUR PERSONAL DATA FOR AND WHY
Where we process your personal data because of our contract
We process these items of your personal data to enter into or fulfil contracts for the purchase,
licensing and support of our products:
                  Reason or purpose                                 Personal Data used
                                                   •    Your contact details;
   Provide you with our products and services and
                                                   •    Purchase and account history;
   maintain your account
                                                   •    Records of your discussions with our teams.
                                                   •    Your contact details;
                                                   •    Website security;
   Maintain your account(s) on the Websites
                                                   •    Account information;
                                                   •    Purchase and account history.
                                                   •    Your contact details;
   Billing, taking payment for our products and    •    Purchase and account history;
   services and performing debt collection         •    Account information;
                                                   •    Payment information.
                                                   •   Your contact details;
   Respond to requests and provide support and
   maintenance for our products                    •   Records of your discussions with our teams;
                                                   •   Product usage.
                                                   •   Your contact details
   Respond to product support requests
                                                   •   Your account and transaction history
Where we process your personal data because we have a legitimate interest
We process these items of your personal data because we have a legitimate interest to improve our
service to you, to identify new products you might be interested in, to advertise our products and
services to you, to verify licensed usage of our products and to detect and reduce abuse by pirates:

                   Reason or purpose                                    Personal Data used
                                                      •    Contact details;
                                                      •    Purchase and account history;
   Determine products and services that may be
                                                      •    Records of your discussions with our teams;
   of interest to you
                                                      •    How you use our websites;
                                                      •    Advertising and direct marketing.
   Direct marketing via email. If, at any time, you
   choose to not to receive direct marketing then     •    Contact details
   we will not send you direct marketing materials.
   Maintain and improve our products and
                                                      •    Records of your discussions with our teams;
   services and provide internal training to staff to
                                                      •    Product usage.
   improve customer experience
   Verify licensed product usage, detect and          •    Contact details;
   reduce abuse by pirates                            •    Product usage.
Where we process your personal data so you can’t be identified any more
We may anonymise and aggregate any of the personal data we hold (so that it does not identify
you). We may use anonymised and aggregated information for purposes that include testing our IT
systems, research, data analysis, improving our Websites, developing new products and services or
improving our existing portfolio.
7.     SOURCES WE COLLECT YOUR PERSONAL DATA FROM
We collect personal data from a range of different sources but primarily directly from you. We collect
personal data by the following means:
•      Directly from you: when you set up an account with us, email us, purchase products or services from
       us, submit information via our Websites, complete any forms or surveys we provide to you, request
       product trials, enter competitions or prize draws, use our products and services, raise queries, make
       a complaint, submit support requests, contact us by phone, email or communicate with us directly
       in some other way.
•      Our Websites: when you create an account on one of our Websites and when you use or visit the
       Websites.
•      Publicly available sources: we make use of public records including your company website, industry
       publications, industry news websites, LinkedIn and professional listings.
•      Government, public authorities and regulators: may provide us with information about you where
       they are required to do so by law or where you have contacted them.

8.     WHO WE SHARE YOUR PERSONAL DATA WITH
In certain circumstances, we will share your personal data with third parties:
                 Who                                              Examples of Sharing
                                        Where you make purchases from www.madewithmischief.com, we
   Companies in the same group of
                                        share that data with other group companies in order to process the
   companies as us
                                        payment and deliver the product to you.
                                        If you are located in a region where we have an approved reseller of
                                        our products and: (a) you have previously purchased our products
                                        via an approved reseller; (b) we believe your needs are better served
                                        by dealing with a local approved reseller; or (c) we believe you are
   Approved Resellers                   pirating our software, then we may pass your contact details and
                                        your purchase and account history to that authorised reseller. In
                                        addition, we may provide details of your product usage if we believe
                                        that you are pirating our software. We will not share your contact
                                        details with a reseller in a different region to you.
                                        If you pay us via debit or credit card, via paypal or another third party
   Payment agents                       payment service then we will share details with the relevant payment
                                        agent so that they can process the transaction.
                                        If you have an overdue debt which is owing to us, if we believe that
   Debt collection, prevention of
                                        you are using pirated version(s) of our products or if we believe that
   piracy and enforcing license
                                        you have breached our agreement(s), we may pass your details to
   agreements
                                        local debt collection agencies or lawyers.
                                        Where we are required to do so by law or to assist with their
   The government or regulators         investigations or initiatives, including, in the UK, the Information
                                        Commissioner’s Office
                                        To assist with the investigation and prevention of crime, including
   Police and law enforcement
                                        software piracy.
                                        We use IT systems and cloud platforms for our everyday business
   IT and cloud service providers,      functions including email, financial management, data storage and
   support teams and advisors           customer account records. We also engage third parties to support
                                        our systems and help us deliver services to you.
                                        If we sell or buy any business or assets, or the shareholders in our
                                        corporate group decide to sell any shares, we may disclose your
   Business acquisitions
                                        personal data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business,
                                        assets or shares.
We do not buy any marketing lists from external providers, nor do we sell your information to any other
company or entity.
Our Websites may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of our partner networks,
advertisers and affiliates. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites

and any services that may be accessible through them have their own privacy policies and that we
do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies or for any personal data that may be
collected through these websites or services.
9.     TRANSFERRING YOUR DATA INTERNATIONALLY
If you live in a country in the EEA, the data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored
at, a destination outside the EEA. It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who
work for us or for one of our suppliers. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer,
storing or processing.
To ensure that your personal data is secure, we will only transfer information to a country outside of
the EEA where we do so in accordance with the GDPR. This requires that one of the following
conditions apply:
•      the European commission has decided that the country provides an adequate level of protection
       for your personal data (in accordance with Article 45 of the GPDR);
•      the transfer is subject to a legally binding and enforceable commitment on the recipient to protect
       the personal data (in accordance with Article 46 of the GDPR);
•      the transfer is made subject to binding corporate rules (in accordance with Article 47 of the GDPR);
       or
•      the transfer is based on an exemption from the GDPR restrictions on transferring personal data
       outside of the EU (in accordance with Article 49).
10. AUTOMATED DECISION MAKING AND PROFILING
Automated decision making happens when a computer uses personal data to make decisions about
a person without any human intervention which have legal effects or similarly significant effects for
the person. We do not engage in any form of automated decision making.
Profiling happens when a computer system uses personal data to evaluate a person’s characteristics.
We undertake profiling in the following areas of our business:
            Type of Profiling                       Logic Used             Potential Consequences for You
                                         We     collect   and   combine   The combined data helps our
                                         personal data, including your    Sales team determine which
   To understand your preferences
                                         purchase and account history     products and services we should
                                         and how you use websites, to     bring to your attention.

                                      better understand your buying
                                      habits     and   your    product
                                      interests.
                                      We       analyse    mismatches
                                                                         Our Customer Conversion team
                                      between product usage and
                                                                         may investigate the mismatch
  To prevent piracy of our software   account information to identify
                                                                         and determine whether or not to
                                      unlicensed use of our products
                                                                         pursue unlicensed users.
                                      and services.
11. HOW LONG WE KEEP YOUR DATA
We will keep your personal data for as long as necessary in order to achieve the purpose of data
processing plus, where necessary, an extended period to cover statutory limitation periods.
12. YOUR RIGHTS IN RELATION TO YOUR PERSONAL DATA
Under certain circumstances, you have the following rights in relation to your personal data:
•    The right of access to your personal data: This enables you to receive a copy of the personal
     information we hold about you and check that we are lawfully processing it.
•    The right to have your personal data rectified: This enables you to have any incomplete or
     inaccurate information we hold about you corrected.
•    The right to deletion of your personal data: This enables you to ask us to delete or remove personal
     information where there is no good reason for us continuing to process it, you withdraw your
     consent, we are unlawfully holding your personal data or we should erase your personal data to
     comply with applicable EU law. You also have the right to ask us to delete or remove your personal
     information where you have exercised your right to object to processing (see below).
•    The right to object to processing of your personal data: This applies where we are relying on a
     legitimate interest (or those of a third party) as a legal basis for our processing and there is
     something about your particular situation which makes you want to object to processing on this
     ground. You also have the right to object where we are processing your personal information for
     direct marketing purposes.
•    The right to restriction of processing of your personal data: This enables you to ask us to suspend
     the processing of personal data about you, for example if you want us to establish its accuracy or
     stop us deleting personal data which you need for a legal claim.
•    The right to have your data transferred to another services provider: This enables you to have the
     personal data you have provided us to be transferred to another party.

You can exercise your rights at any time by contacting us at legal@foundry.com and providing
sufficient information for us to identify you and your personal data.
We will always aim to help you when you wish to exercise your rights but in some instances we may
have lawful grounds to reject your request depending on the legal reason why we collected your
personal data. You will, though, always have the right to be informed about the information we
collect about you.
We will investigate any request you make without undue delay and in any event within one month of
receipt of your request. That period may be extended by two further months where necessary, taking
into account the complexity and number of requests. We shall inform you of any such extension
within one month of receipt of the request, together with the reasons for the delay.
In the event that we decide to not take action on the request, we will inform you of the reasons for
not taking action.
13. COOKIES
Cookies are very small text files that are stored on your computer device when you use it to visit
many websites. We use cookies to distinguish you from other users, by tracking visitor behaviour and
storing certain site preferences. This helps us to provide you with a good experience when you use
or browse the website and also allows us to improve our products, services and the website.
If you prefer not to allow the use of cookies, you can change the configuration of your browser to
either warn you when you receive a cookie or to automatically reject them. However, you may find
that disabling cookies means that certain areas of our site do not function correctly.
If you would like to find out more about cookies, including how to control or delete them, then we
recommend you visit http://www.aboutcookies.org for detailed guidance.
What types of cookies do we use?
•      Session cookies: A session cookie remembers your login for you and what you have put in your
       shopping basket. We consider these to be strictly necessary for the working of our Website. If these
       are disabled, then various functions on our site will not work.
•      Google Analytics and Optimize: We use this tool to understand how the website is being used and
       conduct user experiments so as to improve user experience. The user data is anonymous.
•      Facebook: Cookies and pixels are used to understand and deliver ads and make them more
       relevant to you. We may also use a cookie to learn whether someone who saw an advert on
       Facebook later visited our Website.
•      OptinMonster: We use this tool to display pop up banners to users. The cookies hide pop up
       banners from successful conversions and for those who would rather sign up the next time.

•      Pardot: We use this tool for email and automation. The cookies help us to track your use of the
       Website to understand the pages you visit. The user data is anonymous.
•      Hotjar: We use this tool to better understand online behavior and opinions of users of our Website
       to improve the Website's user experience and performance/conversion rates. The tool uses cookies
       to record participation in polls and control related pop ups and poll widgets.
•      Third Party Tags: we use tools provided by LinkedIn and Twitter to track conversions, retarget
       website visitors, and understand usage habits of members interacting with our Website.
•      Third Party Videos: where we embed and you access videos from Vimeo, Wistia or YouTube, those
       organisations may set their own cookies in accordance with their own privacy policies.
14. SECURITY
We know security matters and take steps to protect your personal data.
Any payment transactions carried out by us or our chosen third-party provider of payment processing
services will be encrypted using Secured Sockets Layer technology or Transport Layer Security.
Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password that enables you to access certain
parts of our website, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to
share a password with anyone.
Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we
will take all reasonable measures to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of
your data transmitted to our site. Any transmission is at your own risk.
15. CHANGES TO THIS NOTICE
This Notice has been updated in May 2018. We reserve the right to amend our Notice and any
changes we may make in the future will be posted on this page.
This Notice will be reviewed and updated on an annual basis to comply with applicable new
requirements, regulations, insights, strategies, processes or technologies. We recommend that you
check for updates to the Privacy & Cookies Policy from time to time but we will notify you directly
about changes to this Notice or the way we use your personal data when we are legally required to
do so.

16. CONTACT AND COMPLAINTS
Questions, comments and requests regarding this Privacy & Cookie Policy are welcomed and should
be addressed to Data & Privacy Policy Enquiries, The Foundry Visionmongers Ltd, 5 Golden Square,
London W1F 9HT, UK or legal@foundry.com.
If you do not agree with a decision we make in relation to a rights request or believe that we are in
breach of applicable data protection laws then you can lodge a complaint with a data protection
supervisory authority in the EU. You can contact the data protection supervisory authority for the UK
using its contact details on its website https://ico.org.uk/.
